## Jake Ockerby

#### **Data Scientist**

+44 7496343453

https://github.com/jakeockerby

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/jakeockerby-a63151196

@ jakeockerby@gmail.com

# Skills —

R

Matlab

SQL

**Statistics** 

Machine Learning

#### Education

2017-2022

BSc. First Class Honours Mathematics

Manchester Metropolitan University

#### Experience

2021 - 2022

**Data Scientist** 

The Insights Family

The Insights Family is a market researcher that surveys parents and children worldwide on a wide range of topics, including favourite films, hobbies and brands. My activites here include:

- Developed machine learning models to predict the success of films amongst children. This project was the result of a collaboration between The Insights Family and MMU, and was used to form the main focus of my final year dissertation.
- Utilised time series analysis techniques to predict the increase and decrease of unique responses on surveys.
- Employed various API sources to gather timezone, weather and demographic data; communicated with software developers to deploy these insights in an interactive and client-friendly way.

2020 - 2021

Data Science Placement Student

The Insights Family

- Created a tool that allowed for deep insight into the database, that could quickly deliver important facts to the customer success department. This meant that reports could be published with much greater efficiency to clients.
- Performed statistical tests on various datasets, identifying if increases or decreases of survey responses were statistically significant.
- Collaborated with other data scientists in data cleaning survey responses from open-ended questions, involving the use of NLP techniques.

### **About Me**

Mathematics graduate with almost 2 years experience as a data scientist. I am passionate about the real-world applications of mathematics especially at the present time in areas such as computing and statistics, where never before has mathematics had such a prominent role.

I have developed a deep interest in data science and have taught myself how to gather, clean, train and test models, and present findings from my data.

In my spare time I participate in Taekwondo, in which I am a 1st Dan Black Belt. I also enjoy reading, and I am currently learning German.